<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Minimal Blog - @lekoarts/gatsby-theme-minimal-blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal website of Shreyas Gupta]]></description><link>https://shreyasgupta.me</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 10:41:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The lockdown weblog]]></title><link>https://shreyasgupta.me/blog/coronavirus-lockdown-weblog-series</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://shreyasgupta.me/blog/coronavirus-lockdown-weblog-series</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;1qkf438&quot;&gt;.css-1qkf438{font-size:1.25rem;-webkit-letter-spacing:-0.003em;-moz-letter-spacing:-0.003em;-ms-letter-spacing:-0.003em;letter-spacing:-0.003em;line-height:1.625;--baseline-multiplier:0.179;--x-height-multiplier:0.35;}@media screen and (min-width:640px){.css-1qkf438{font-size:1.25rem;}}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;I was on my way down to the common mess at my uni when I read an email stating that our ongoing sports fest has been canceled and the uni is under lockdown. Things got chaotic pretty quickly after that. Students were hoarding the canteen in fear of scarcity and many were in a hurry to leave the campus. Luckily I was able to come back home via road amidst fear of &lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;wbxg5e&quot;&gt;.css-wbxg5e{color:var(--theme-ui-colors-primary,#9f7aea);-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-wbxg5e:hover{-webkit-text-decoration:underline;text-decoration:underline;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/science/2020/01/how-coronavirus-spreads-on-a-plane/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt;airborne transmission in flights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 outbreak has wreck havoc in many countries, especially India, which will be in rubbles if community spread gets serious. A countrywide lockdown was initiated on 22nd March to contain the spread, which has been extended since then to April 14th. The following entries will go about my retrospective thoughts on the various changes that I have incorporated in my daily routine, updates on the outbreak and many more things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;g61uz2&quot;&gt;.css-g61uz2{font-family:inherit;font-weight:700;line-height:1.25;margin:0;margin-bottom:0.25rem;font-size:1.5rem;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Research work, hoardings and fake news&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;aiqw19&quot;&gt;.css-aiqw19{color:var(--theme-ui-colors-secondary,#7f8ea3);font-size:1rem;margin-top:0;margin-bottom:0;}@media screen and (min-width:640px){.css-aiqw19{font-size:1.25rem;}}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;22nd March, day 1&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;8 hours into the lockdown and I&amp;#x27;m already starting to feel claustrophobic. It&amp;#x27;s weird as I generally think going out is a chore, unless we&amp;#x27;re eating of course. For now we&amp;#x27;ve stocked up of veggies and eggs but these youtube cooking vids are depleting our stock quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;The lockdown is messing with my academic plans for the year. I&amp;#x27;ll have to resort to telephonic study for my research as participant observation is out of the picture. My plans to visit Sweden in August for my 20 credit project will probably get delayed too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand why Indians like blowing things out of proportion. The man on the top asks us to clap, and we start performing Garba and have processions of men and women banging kitchen utensils while chanting &amp;quot;go corona, go&amp;quot;. Meanwhile the virus is waiting outside our porch like John Travolta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;Panic shopping and grocery hoardings are going to cause a lot of problems. Grocery delivery services like Big Basket and Grofers have stopped showing delivery slots. I&amp;#x27;m surprised that things didn&amp;#x27;t go down with these services like Instacart and Amazon, with their workers calling are demanding extended sick pay, health coverage and increased tip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;24th March, day 3&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;To ensure the safety of our maids, drivers and even our own, we had to give them paid leave. This means we need to clean our own dishes, do laundry, clean the house and any other chore which you can think of. 2 days in and I can say it with confidence that we are heavily dependent on the so-called &amp;quot;unskilled&amp;quot; labor. Oh how the turntables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Houseparty and until tomorrow&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;25th March, day 4&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;Back in October 2018, I downloaded houseparty, a video chat app which is very similar to Snapchat in terms of design, in other words, pathetic. Obviously I deleted it, like I did to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/19/ello-again/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt;Ello&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/26/20833903/facebook-instagram-threads-messaging-app-close-friends-snapchat&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt; Threads&lt;/a&gt; by Instagram and devrant. Today morning I saw a couple of instagram stories of groups of friends playing pictionary in a video chat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Fake news and the Houseparty scam&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;31st March, day 10&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;Can we talk about how ridiculously fast information is spreading during this crisis? Lot of discussions opened online in the last two years about fake news and misinformation but I always looked past it until now. Whatsapp has emerged as de facto standard for sowing the seeds of a fake piece of information, and I&amp;#x27;ll show you how with 2 incidents which happened this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;I woke up today morning to my mom screaming on the phone, &amp;quot;Are you serious? She&amp;#x27;s positive? oh my god!&amp;quot;. One of my mom&amp;#x27;s friends heard about a positive case in the apartment and immediately shared it with everyone. My mom immediately called up the family, who were confused as the kid was totally fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;I live in Film Nagar, a relatively lavish locality with quite a few places to hang out. We had 6 international travellers in our apartments who returned less than a week back, and were under quarantined as per government regulations. They had daily checkups done by GHMC officials who had also put up posters to notify everyone in the apartment/vicinity about these students who have travel history. It&amp;#x27;s a common protocol being followed in many countries right now. Turns out someone had mass forwarded messages on Whatsapp that our apartment had 6 positive cases and was locked down. Along with it was an image of a metal gate with a huge &amp;quot;Quarantined red zone&amp;quot; banner which wasn&amp;#x27;t even our gate, and images of the GHMC posters of each student.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;My whatsapp inbox blew up by evening. Mom and Dad had to answer around 150 calls and explain how the whole thing is an hoax. There were a few local news websites who were posting about it. It just took around 12 hours for that message to fool hundreds of families and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:960px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:71.25%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAOCAYAAAAvxDzwAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAAB7UlEQVQ4y5WS32sTQRDHT01Kc2kFQ0Hvdvf2fv++a2Ot+dUGkmArKjEULBWsFQxFivhSUfHhnorv/onCyfkuiEKX8e6a3JOY68AwAzv72Z3vDMf93zqpT1J/MvMsb2cHAMCVMoJoHiuV5ZquGAkSJRAEAURBBBFhkFQ9rnLcclYjIrIYGPqbeTSpUG82ez8Gw8ewt/footvdvmi1uhBubH2/fUfgsxrHW18M7Pd785T/ePo8mR4fQhA2mWlazDAdUFQzXuK4WlaAEV4MHIz2C+Cns6/Jy6MzcFwrB1JZB6qYcaM+AxJpMRDJgzzadY4X7M+Jar8A11GYRGRGJAWwpMZiYykHojI/lOhc6Crv3jeSYMMFy3QYQohhIgMmSiyurZYHDpE+yyr82zBIJl4AkmEyLCImqyYomh2v3LhsmZRpeTwcFRp+eX+SnB4dgOuvM5lSlsJANfy4xl0BeG/nYQHcPY6S0eQ1uJbBCKFMoipQWYsbNy81xLjEHmredgFs775JNntjUBXK0ssM50PRYuFWtbyG46fjAhhFH+Lpq8N094w/mqb9xpimQOWbsLZSHoiNuwWwc/DuV//ZFHzbAs8PwDC9bCg/69evoKGse/P0Wu/B/km4tXPebrWiTqcbyYp+Tqg2XZ0//g8N/wIZIomb24WfTgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image css-0&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of Houseparty download&quot; title=&quot;screenshot of Houseparty download&quot; src=&quot;/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/7d769/imag1.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/5243c/imag1.png 240w,/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/ab158/imag1.png 480w,/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/7d769/imag1.png 960w,/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/87339/imag1.png 1440w,/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/88b03/imag1.png 1920w,/static/d91eb0c9c42ea49b14cf7bf2757008ed/9fabd/imag1.png 2000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Dalgona coffee&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;1st april, day 11&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;In today&amp;#x27;s episode of &amp;quot;Another viral tiktok&amp;quot;, let&amp;#x27;s look at the internet sensation which made people without hand blenders, whip coffee, sugar and water with a freakin&amp;#x27; spoon. If you&amp;#x27;re a millenial like me, you might have already tried your hands at making this, but let me tell you something, I hate this concept. For starters, we need to acknowledge that this is yet another &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/4789145/avocado-latte-australia/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt;latte in avocado&lt;/a&gt; bullshit by the kids on insta, which means it is the aesthetics and the process which makes it elegant, not the dish itself. The creamy sweet coffee froth looks cute floating on top of the milk and ice slurry, but only till you&amp;#x27;re done posting a story on insta and sending 178 snaps. I have no clue how people managed to get the coffee to mix with the milk as the low density froth is extremely adament about socialising with anything! After battling my mason jar with a spoon for 15 minutes, I threw everything in a blender, something I would&amp;#x27;ve done in the first place if it wasn&amp;#x27;t for the curse of attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;css-g61uz2&quot;&gt;Self haircut&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h5 class=&quot;css-aiqw19&quot;&gt;3rd April, day 13&lt;/h5&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hackathons, the ice cream trucks of the tech industry.]]></title><link>https://shreyasgupta.me/blog/hackathons-gehealthcare-and-more</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://shreyasgupta.me/blog/hackathons-gehealthcare-and-more</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;1qkf438&quot;&gt;.css-1qkf438{font-size:1.25rem;-webkit-letter-spacing:-0.003em;-moz-letter-spacing:-0.003em;-ms-letter-spacing:-0.003em;letter-spacing:-0.003em;line-height:1.625;--baseline-multiplier:0.179;--x-height-multiplier:0.35;}@media screen and (min-width:640px){.css-1qkf438{font-size:1.25rem;}}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;max-width:960px&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:66.66666666666666%;position:relative;bottom:0;left:0;background-image:url(&amp;#x27;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAANABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQBAv/EABYBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAAv/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABZNRPaFh//8QAGhABAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIAAxEiMv/aAAgBAQABBQIet1zEISbKMfE7AP/EABoRAAEFAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAhEhMVH/2gAIAQMBAT8B1aJbw//EABkRAAIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAASAiExUf/aAAgBAgEBPwFa0WXT/8QAHRAAAwABBQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIQIiMTJRof/aAAgBAQAGPwKJWFelG1KGHDPHh0+n/8QAGxAAAwEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIUExgZH/2gAIAQEAAT8hlskEOcvvkVNzTpZ5RHdX0EVH0f/aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQFB//xAAXEQEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEh/9oACAEDAQE/EMoBEGnU/8QAFxEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQAhUf/aAAgBAgEBPxAelXGf/8QAHxABAQABAgcAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBUWGRodHx/9oACAEBAAE/ECEfWa+cZUASsdxxaJpt/eQqRMhZiYWuwQvNjgMw4fTP/9k=&amp;#x27;);background-size:cover;display:block&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image css-0&quot; alt=&quot;picture of shreyas and tanishq discussing&quot; title=&quot;picture of shreyas and tanishq discussing&quot; src=&quot;/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/18e3b/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/46946/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 240w,/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/55489/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 480w,/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/18e3b/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 960w,/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/60e21/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 1440w,/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/69b48/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 1920w,/static/966b3b2cedf9aeb63864a3eb93223c09/47432/GE-healthcare-hackathon-image1.jpg 5308w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;We had 8 crushed cans of Red Bulls, 4 packets of half eaten chips, two pairs of drowsy red eyes and 8 hours left. I hadn’t slept in days and all we had seen was code from the past 6 days. This was our first hackathon at GE Healthcare’s JFWTC campus, Bengaluru. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;For students, hackathons are like ice cream trucks — selling swag, goodies and a carnival ticket. They romanticise the world of code and silicon, glittering it with ridiculous dumps of food and cash. The effectiveness of such large scale hackathons to incubate innovation, which depend heavily on extrinsic factors of motivation to attract students, can be debated. Or one could argue that the idea is not to innovate, but to rather encourage students to indulge in this field. Either way, we were sold on the idea. We were desperately looking for one for weeks and luckily fell upon GEHC’s &lt;style data-emotion-css=&quot;wbxg5e&quot;&gt;.css-wbxg5e{color:var(--theme-ui-colors-primary,#9f7aea);-webkit-text-decoration:none;text-decoration:none;}.css-wbxg5e:hover{-webkit-text-decoration:underline;text-decoration:underline;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvWekOpNp0s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt;precision challenge Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;. It had an ideation phase followed by a 24-hour on-site implementation challenge. We submitted our proposal within hours and were surprisingly amongst 36 teams all over India invited for the 24-hour coding sprint. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;We made our very first &lt;em class=&quot;css-0&quot;&gt;oopsy&lt;/em&gt; by going to the event with very little preparation, and It’s virtually impossible to complete a data science project with a front-end in a measly 24 hours. Nevertheless, we woke up that morning, barely showered and grabbed an Uber to JFWTC. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;The place was ridiculous. They had this pantry setup with continental breakfast, a mini bakery (nothing was mini about it tbh), juice bar and an ice bowl with dozens of Red Bulls just waiting to get you diabetic. After a small introductory session, we all got our workstations for the rest of the night. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;css-1qkf438&quot;&gt;Things weren’t going well for us. Our idea was to build a dataset generator for dermatology clinics (later expanded to general medical imagery datasets) which will remove any personal identifiers based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hipaajournal.com/hipaa-compliance-checklist/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;css-wbxg5e&quot;&gt;HIPAA regulations&lt;/a&gt;. In simpler terms, it was an electron app (geez, I know) in which you dump your images and we will clean it by removing identifiers like eyes, lips, textual information, etc. The problem was that it was just the two of us, and we weren’t familiar with front end very well. I managed to bootstrap together a cleaning engine by midnight and we started working on developing a presentable demo. We had 8 more hours left and we were trying to figure out how to dump our engine output in the app (It’s ridiculously simple btw). I had given up on my dreams of holding a giant cheque like Michael Scott and took a nap, and boy was it a long nap.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>